castrol.com 2018-08-16

# Privacy Statement | Castrol United Kingdom | Castrol Global Home

## Information about our Organisation and Website 

    Castrol respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it. We provide this Privacy Statement to inform you of our privacy practices and how your personal information is used and protected by Castrol. This website is governed by the laws of England. The courts of England shall have exclusive jurisdiction over any dispute arising out of your use of this website. 
    
    The castrol.com/uk website is owned by Castrol Limited, Castrol Technology Centre, Whitchurch Hill, Pangbourne, Berkshire, RG8 7QR. Registered in the UK: 149435

### Collection and Use of Personal Information

    This Privacy Statement sets out the basis on which Castrol collects and usesyour personal information.  Personal information is data that can identify a specific individual such as name, physical and/or email address and telephone number. If during your visit to this website you order products or services, enter a competition or promotion or otherwise submit information to us e.g., by filling in forms or responding to surveys, you are choosing to provide us with your personal information.  We will use it to provide the information, products or services you request. We may also use your personal information to contact you with information on additional products and/or services which Castrol reasonably thinks may be of interest to you.  For more information see the “Direct Marketing” section below.  
    Where you have subscribed to receive our newsletter(s), we are able to ensure you receive further relative and informative communications by following your interactions with that communication, such as whether you receive, open or click on a link within an email communication.  We offer you an unsubscribe in all our further communications. 

### Direct Marketing

    Castrol may send you marketing communications (including by email) in line with your previously expressed marketing preferences. If you no longer wish to receive such communications, please contact us at [lubesmarketing@castrol.com](mailto:lubesmarketing@castrol.com) to modify your preferences, or follow the opt-out instructions contained in each marketing communication.

### Disclosures and Transfers of Personal Information 

    Castrol does not sell or otherwise release your personal information to third parties to allow them to direct market their products and services to you. In order to provide our products and services we may, however, need to share your personal information with other companies within the BP Group, and/or third party service providers that process data on our behalf.  
    
    Since Castrol operates globally, Castrol may want to transfer your personal information to other countries, including countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA). However, while in our control, we always seek to ensure that your personal information receives the same level of protection as it would had it stayed within the EEA, including seeking to ensure that it is kept secure and used only in accordance with our instructions and for the agreed purpose(s). 
    
    We reserve the right to disclose your personal information as required by law, or when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, request from a regulator or any other legal process served on Castrol. In the event that Castrol is subject to a takeover, divestment or acquisition we may disclose your personal information to the new owner of the business.

### Site Traffic Information and Cookies

    Servers located within Castrol and hosted by third party service providers (which may be located outside the EEA) automatically log data about your visit to this website based on your IP address.  Castrol uses this information to see where the website is being used in the world to ensure seamless coverage.
    
    Castrol uses cookies for a number of purposes to improve the functionality of this website. These are discussed in more detail below. To delete or stop cookies being placed on your computer refer to the help menu on your internet browser. In a few cases, blocking cookies may reduce the functionality of some websites or prevent access to them depending on your chosen browser options. Cookies can be “session cookies” (which are deleted when you close your browser) and/or “persistent cookies” which remain on your computer for a longer period of time.For further information about cookies, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org.](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/ "Opens in new window")  
    
    This website uses cookies which:
    
    (a)	are strictly necessary to enable you to move around the site and use its features, e.g. accessing secured areas.  Without these cookies some of the services you’ve asked for cannot be provided.  
    
    (b)	enhance the performance of the website by collecting information about how visitors use it (e.g. to analyse the number of website visitors that view a particular page).  
    
    (c)	increase the website’s functionality and make it more personal to you by allowing us to remember your previous choices (e.g., your location and preferred font type and size) and to provide any enhanced features detailed in the cookie-specific user notice.  
    
    The information that these cookies collect is not used to identify who you are, send you targeted advertising or remember where you’ve been on the internet.  By continuing to use this website, you agree to our use of cookies as described above and youagreethat your attention was specifically drawn to this section of our privacy statement and to the explicit cookies notice.

### Security

    Transmission of information via the internet is not always secure.  We cannot guarantee the security of your data while being transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk.  However, once we have received your information, we take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorised access, improper use or disclosure, unauthorised modification or unlawful destruction or accidental loss of personal information once it is under our control.  

### Keeping Personal Information Accurate & Access

    We are committed to ensuring that your personal information is kept accurate and up to date. However, we can only make changes to your personal information if you notify us. It is your responsibility to let us know if there are inaccuracies or changes to your personal information.  Please notify us at [lubesmarketing@castrol.com](mailto:lubesmarketing@castrol.com) if there are any changes to or inaccuracies in your personal information, providing us with sufficient information to enable us to identify you, so that any changes can be made.
    
    In accordance with our internal policies and UK law, you may ask us to provide you with access to any personal data we process about you. If you want access to your personal information contact [lubesmarketing@castrol.com](mailto:lubesmarketing@castrol.com). We may be able to charge you for providing such access.  

### Hyperlinks and Embedded Functionality

    Our website may contain links to content or other functionality provided by third parties which are outside our control and are not covered by our privacy statement, including the embedded search box facility: The search box on this website (“Search Box”) is powered by Google Inc (“Google”).  You acknowledge and agree that Google’s privacy policy (located at <http://www.google.com/privacy.html>) shall apply to your use of the Search Box and by using the Search Box you consent to Google using your personal data in accordance with its privacy policy.  Similarly, if you access other websites using links or use other embedded functionality provided by third parties, the operators of those websites may collect information from or about you which will be used by them in accordance with their privacy statement, which may differ from ours. We encourage you to read those providers’ privacy statements on their websites.  We do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies.

### Children

    Castrol does not knowingly collect information from children.

### Questions About Your Personal Information

    If you have any questions relating to this privacy statement or the personal information we hold about you please contact us by email at [lubesmarketing@castrol.com](mailto:lubesmarketing@castrol.com) or by post at the following address:Digital Marketing, Castrol UK Ltd, Castrol Technology Centre, Whitchurch Hill, Pangbourne, Berkshire, RG8 7QR.

### Changes to this Privacy Statement

    We review this privacy statement regularly and may modify it from time to time.  We will place any updates on this webpage. By continuing to use this website after such changes have been made, you acknowledge and agree you have read, understood and accept the changes.
